codeitwell.com 2011-11-06

# Privacy | Helping Online Entrepreneurs

**Overview**

CodeItWell.com, Inc. is a blog for programmers on the web and this "Privacy Statement" discloses the privacy practices for the entire CodeItWell.com website and CodeItWell.com respects your privacy. Below is an outline of the information that CodeItWell.com gathers, how it’s used, and how you can "opt-out".

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may [contact us](http://www.codeitwell.com/contact).

**Statement**

CodeItWell.com respects your right to privacy. Because we gather certain types of information about our users we want to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses the types of information we gather and how we use it.

**What Information does CodeItWell.com collect ?**

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with the best and most useful content and services. Because we derive revenue mainly from advertising, collecting information is essential to keep our services affordable to users.

We collect personal information about our users during usage of the CodeItWell.com service, from our use of 'cookie' technology as you use the service and during sending or viewing a thread or an article through CodeItWell.com or while subscribing to our forums section for email notifications.

Whenever you request a page through your browser, navigation and click stream data such as:

  * Your IP address.
  * Browser and version.
  * Operating system.
  * Date and time.
  * The referral site

are stored in a log file and/or database. Any search terms that you enter into the CodeItWell Site Search are also logged. This information cannot be used to identify specific individuals, and is only used for:

  * Website and system administration.
  * Research and development.
  * Anonymous user analysis.
  * To provide accurate statistics to advertisers in the form of aggregated data.

This information is kept on a secure dedicated server.

The email addresses collected from the forums are not sold, or disclosed to any third parties. These addresses will only be used by our business to send out whatever you request us to send. You will not receive any mailings you did not request.

**What is CodeItWell.com's practice regarding cookies ?**

Your Internet browser has a feature called "cookies" which stores small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to Internet websites. You do not need to have cookies turned on to visit CodeItWell.com. Cookies alone tell us nothing about who you are unless you specifically give us personally identifiable information which we may use to enhance your services in the ways described below. You may choose not to allow cookies to be collected by adjusting your settings on your browser.

Cookies on this site are used by ourselves, our ad management system, and occasionally by advertisers who use 3rd party ad serving solutions. Cookies are used for:

  * Ad tracking.
  * Storing login information
  * Statistical site-traffic analysis.
  * Keeping count of return visits to our website or our advertisers' or partners' websites.

We allow other companies that are presenting advertisements on our websites and, sometimes, in our newsletters to use tracking technology on your computer. We do not give any personally identifiable information to them as part of this relationship. Unless you visit the website of these companies and provide them with personally identifiable information about yourself, these tracking technologies tell those advertisers nothing about who you are. Our advertisers' use of tracking technology is subject to their own privacy policies.

**How does CodeItWell.com use the information it collects ?**

The information collected during the registration process for the CodeItWell.com Community is used to:

  * Customize content based upon user preferences
  * Contact members
  * Display member status
  * Display the date of a member´s last visit.
  * Enable automatic log-ins upon further visits.
  * Determining which features our overall user population likes best.
  * To enhance the user experience in our website.

Information collected in this process can also be used to prevent banned users from re-registering under a different username.

**How does CodeItWell.com share this information and with whom ?**

We aggregate personally identifiable information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for marketing, promotional, and other purposes. We do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to identify you personally. For example, we may tell our business partners how many customers in certain demographic groups access some articles.

**What is CodeItWell.com's practice regarding IP addresses ?**

We collect and analyze traffic though Google Analytics on our website by keeping track of the IP addresses of our visitors. IP addresses are unique numeric identifiers that are assigned to each computer browser accessing the Internet. An IP address, by itself, cannot identify you personally. However, when combined with other information provided by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), your IP address can be used to identify the computer originating a message.

CodeItWell.com uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secured. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information. CodeItWell.com also links to a wide variety of other websites. We are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users.

**How does CodeItWell.com handle 3rd Party Advertising ?**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. Our third-party advertising companies also separately places or recognizes a cookie file on your browser in the course of delivering advertisements to this website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit their respective privacy policies.

**Questions and Comments**

If you have any questions, comments or suggestions regarding our web site's privacy policy, or regarding any other aspects of our website, please [contact us](http://www.codeitwell.com/contact).

**Notification of Changes**

If we decide to change the Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted [here](http://www.codeitwell.com/privacy)
